Hello English learners.
英语学习者你们好。
Welcome back to another great lesson here with EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're bringing you an upper intermediate lesson.
今天我们为大家带来一堂中高级课程。
A special lesson about the new president.
一堂关于新总统的特别课程。
Right.
没错。
It's been a hot topic in the US, the new president elect, President Obama.
在美国，新当选的总统奥巴马一直是个热门话题。
Yes.
是的。
So today we're bringing you something that you might see at his inaugural address.
所以今天我们带来一些你可能会在他的就职演说中看到的内容。
That's true.
确实如此。
So Marco, can you explain this word, inaugural address?
那么Marco，你能解释一下“inaugural address”这个词吗？
The inaugural address is the first speech the president gives at the ceremony when he
就职演说就是总统在正式就职典礼上发表的第一次演讲。
is officially president.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
明白了。
So it's his first presidential speech.
所以这是他作为总统的第一次演讲。
Exactly.
正是。
Great.
太好了。
So let's take a look at some other words that we're going to find in the dialogue today
那么让我们看看今天对话中会出现的其他一些单词，在词汇预览部分。
in vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
All right.
好的。
On vocabulary preview today we have two words.
今天的词汇预览有两个单词。
The first one is swear in.
第一个是“swear in”。
Swear in.
Swear in。
We'll see this word in its past tense in the dialogue, right?
我们会在对话中看到它的过去式，对吧？
Sworn in.
Sworn in。
So it means?
那么它的意思是？
So to swear someone in is to officially give that person a very important position.
“swear someone in”就是正式授予某人一个非常重要的职位。
Right.
对。
Usually in government.
通常是在政府中。
Yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
And our second word is oath.
我们的第二个单词是“oath”。
Oath.
Oath。
O-A-T-H, oath.
O-A-T-H，oath。
And oath goes hand in hand with swear in, right?
宣誓和就职是紧密相连的，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
When you swear someone in, they make an oath.
当你让某人宣誓就职时，他们会做出一个誓言。
A promise, right?
一个承诺，对吧？
A promise.
一个承诺。
An official promise to carry out the duties of that job.
一个正式承诺，要履行那份工作的职责。
Right.
对。
So they promise that they will do their job.
所以他们承诺会做好自己的工作。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So now let's listen to our dialogue for a first time.
那么现在让我们第一次听一下对话。
Where are we?
我们在哪里？
Well, we're actually watching a news reporter on TV.
嗯，我们实际上在看电视上的一位新闻记者。
She's in Washington and she's going to tell us all about what's happening.
她在华盛顿，她会告诉我们正在发生的一切。
Great.
太好了。
So let's listen.
那我们来听吧。
This is Madeline Wright for BCC News reporting live from Washington, DC, where very shortly
我是马德琳·赖特，BCC新闻从华盛顿特区现场报道，很快
the new president will deliver his inaugural address.
新总统将发表他的就职演说。
Just moments ago, the president was sworn into office following the United States Constitution.
就在几分钟前，总统按照美国宪法宣誓就职。
The president swore an oath to faithfully execute the office of the presidency.
总统宣誓要忠实履行总统职务。
And what exactly is going on now, Madeline?
马德琳，现在到底在发生什么？
Well, Tom, true to American tradition, the band has just played Hail to the Chief and
嗯，汤姆，按照美国传统，乐队刚刚演奏了《向统帅致敬》，
the president has been honored with a 21-gun salute.
总统受到了21响礼炮的致敬。
Now we're waiting for the president to take the stage and deliver his speech.
现在我们正在等待总统上台发表演讲。
Tom, it's like the who's who of the political world here on Capitol Hill, with dignitaries
汤姆，国会山这里简直是政界名流云集，有来自
representing several different countries.
多个国家的显要人物。
What's the mood on the ground like, Madeline?
马德琳，现场的气氛怎么样？
In a word, the mood here is electric.
用一个词来说，这里的气氛非常热烈。
The excitement in the air is palpable.
空气中的兴奋感显而易见。
I've never seen a larger crowd here on Capitol Hill.
我从未在国会山见过这么多人。
The audience is shouting, crying, and embracing each other.
观众们在呼喊、哭泣，互相拥抱。
On this, a most historic day, you can feel the hope and the excitement in the air.
在这个最具历史意义的日子里，你能感受到空气中的希望和兴奋。
The 20th of January will go down in history as the...
1月20日将作为……载入史册。
Oh, Tom, it looks like the president is about to begin.
哦，汤姆，看起来总统要开始了。
My fellow Americans, I stand before you today...
我的美国同胞们，今天我站在你们面前……
Okay, some technical problems at the inaugural address.
好吧，就职演说出现了一些技术问题。
Yeah, I certainly hope this doesn't happen.
是啊，我当然希望这不会发生。
Well, if it does, you heard it first at EnglishPod.
嗯，如果发生了，你是在EnglishPod最先听到的。
Predictors of the future here.
我们是未来的预言者。
Okay, let's take a look at Language Takeaway.
好的，让我们看看语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
On Language Takeaway today, we're bringing you four words.
今天的语言小课堂，我们给你带来四个单词。
The first word is deliver.
第一个单词是 deliver。
Deliver.
Deliver。
Like, deliver a pizza.
比如，送披萨。
No.
不。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
We've got three examples that will show the meaning of this word.
我们有三个例子来展示这个词的含义。
Example one.
例子一。
Who's going to deliver the welcome speech?
谁来致欢迎词？
Example two.
例子二。
I've been asked to deliver a presentation on the findings of our research project.
我被要求就我们研究项目的发现做一个演示。
Example three.
例子三。
Dr. Rosen is delivering a lecture on macroeconomics.
罗森博士正在做一个关于宏观经济学的讲座。
Okay, so deliver a speech.
好的，所以是发表演讲。
Say a speech.
说演讲。
To say a speech.
Yeah.
是的。
So you wouldn't say say a speech, you would say deliver a speech.
所以你不会说“说演讲”，而会说“发表演讲”。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
The next word for Language Takeaway, the who's who.
语言小课堂的下一个词是 the who's who。
The who's who.
The who's who。
So this is a funny expression, hey?
这是个有趣的表达，对吧？
It's kind of weird.
有点奇怪。
The who's who is the important people in a particular field, right?
The who's who 指的是某个特定领域的重要人物，对吧？
Right.
对。
So, for example, there was a party last night and the who's who of the film industry was
比如，昨晚有个派对，电影界的重要人物都
there.
在场。
Whoa, so all the important stars and directors.
哇，所以是所有重要的明星和导演。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So you would say the funeral was like a who's who of the political world.
所以你可以说那个葬礼就像是政界名流的大聚会。
Okay, so all the important political figures were at this funeral.
好的，所以所有重要的政治人物都出席了这场葬礼。
Exactly.
没错。
Let's move to our third word, Dignitaries.
我们来看第三个词，Dignitaries。
Dignitaries.
Dignitaries。
Okay, we have some great examples so you can understand what this word means.
好的，我们有一些很好的例子，这样你就能理解这个词的意思了。
So let's listen.
那么我们来听一听。
Example one.
例子一。
Several important dignitaries were present at the opening ceremony, including the President
几位重要政要出席了开幕式，包括巴西总统、西班牙国王和教皇。
of Brazil, the King of Spain, and the Pope.
巴西总统、西班牙国王和教皇。
Example two.
例子二。
There are going to be a lot of foreign dignitaries at the dinner.
晚宴上会有很多外国政要出席。
So basically we can understand that dignitaries are really important people, right?
所以基本上我们可以理解，政要就是非常重要的人物，对吧？
Right.
对。
Important political or religious figures.
重要的政治或宗教人物。
I see.
我明白了。
All right, now our last word for language takeaway, palpable.
好了，现在我们语言要点的最后一个词是 palpable。
Palpable.
Palpable。
When something is palpable, it's so strong you can feel it.
当某事物是 palpable 时，它强烈到你能感觉到它。
Okay, so it's a very strong feeling.
好的，所以这是一种非常强烈的感觉。
You can almost touch it.
你几乎可以触摸到它。
Yeah, like the excitement was palpable or the fear was palpable.
是的，比如兴奋感 palpable 或恐惧感 palpable。
Okay, interesting word, palpable.
好的，有趣的词，palpable。
Let's listen to our dialogue again and now let's try and listen to all these words we
让我们再听一遍对话，这次试着听出我们刚才讨论的所有这些词。
just talked about.
我们刚才讨论的所有这些词。
This is Madeline Wright for BCC News reporting live from Washington, D.C., where very shortly
我是 BCC 新闻的玛德琳·赖特，正在华盛顿特区进行现场报道，新总统即将发表就职演说。
the new president will deliver his inaugural address.
就在刚才，总统根据美国宪法宣誓就职。
Just moments ago, the president was sworn into office following the United States Constitution.
总统宣誓将忠实履行总统职责。
The president swore an oath to faithfully execute the office of the presidency.
And what exactly is going on now, Madeline?
玛德琳，现在现场情况如何？
Well, Tom, true to American tradition, the band has just played Hail to the Chief and
汤姆，按照美国传统，乐队刚刚演奏了《向统帅致敬》，总统也接受了21响礼炮的致敬。
the president has been honored with a 21-gun salute.
总统也接受了21响礼炮的致敬。
Now we're waiting for the president to take the stage and deliver his speech.
现在我们正在等待总统上台发表演讲。
Tom is like the who's who of the political world here on Capitol Hill with dignitaries
汤姆，国会山上聚集了政界的重要人物，还有代表多个国家的政要。
representing several different countries.
还有代表多个国家的政要。
What's the mood on the ground like, Madeline?
玛德琳，现场气氛如何？
In a word, the mood here is electric.
用一个词来形容，现场气氛非常热烈。
The excitement in the air is palpable.
空气中的兴奋感 palpable。
I've never seen a larger crowd here on Capitol Hill.
我从未在国会山上见过这么多人。
The audience is shouting, crying and embracing each other.
观众们在呼喊、哭泣，互相拥抱。
On this, a most historic day, you can feel the hope and the excitement in the air.
在这个历史性的日子里，你能感受到空气中的希望和兴奋。
The 20th of January will go down in history as the...
1月20日将作为……载入史册。
Oh, Tom, it looks like the president is about to begin.
哦，汤姆，看起来总统要开始了。
My fellow Americans, I stand before you today.
我的美国同胞们，今天我站在你们面前。
Okay, so if you noticed in our dialogue, we have some really interesting phrases there.
好的，如果你注意到我们的对话，里面有一些非常有趣的短语。
Yes.
是的。
So I think it's time for us to take a look at Fluency Builder.
所以我认为是时候看看流利度构建器了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
On Fluency Builder today, we're going to be looking at three phrases that are very interesting
今天的流利度构建器，我们将学习三个非常有趣的短语，
because we can change them a little bit and form different patterns.
因为我们可以稍微改变它们，形成不同的模式。
Yeah.
是的。
So the first phrase we have is, in a word.
第一个短语是：简而言之。
In a word.
简而言之。
We use this expression when we want to describe something in one word.
当我们想用一个词描述某事时，我们会用这个表达。
Right.
对。
Pretty simple, hey?
很简单，对吧？
It's really simple.
确实很简单。
Let's look at the pattern.
我们来看看这个模式。
We've got examples of how you could use this phrase.
我们有一些如何使用这个短语的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
In a word, the situation is serious.
简而言之，情况很严重。
Example two.
例子二。
What's it like there?
那里怎么样？
In a word, it's amazing.
简而言之，太棒了。
Okay, so in a word, this podcast is...
好的，那么简而言之，这个播客是……
Awesome.
棒极了。
Amazing.
太棒了。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, let's look at our second phrase today.
好的，我们来看看今天的第二个短语。
Go down in history.
载入史册。
So this is a really common phrase.
这是一个非常常见的短语。
I'm sure you guys have heard it.
我相信你们肯定听过。
Yeah, basically something that is really important that everyone will remember for a very long
是的，基本上是指非常重要、每个人都会记住很久的事情。
time.
时间。
Let's look at this pattern with a few examples.
我们通过几个例子来看看这个模式。
Example one.
例子一。
This is going to go down in history as the worst disaster the world has ever seen.
这将作为世界从未见过的最严重的灾难载入史册。
Example two.
例子二。
He'll go down in history as the best president we've ever had.
他将作为我们有过的最好的总统载入史册。
Example three.
例子三。
This day will go down in history.
这一天将载入史册。
Okay, so as you can see, the pattern is we're using a superlative.
好的，所以正如你所见，这个模式是我们使用了最高级。
That's right.
没错。
The most.
最……的。
The worst.
最差的。
The worst, right?
最差的，对吧？
And our final phrase in putting it together is...
我们最后组合起来的短语是……
My fellow Americans.
我的美国同胞们。
So obviously you can change this one up a little bit, hey?
所以显然你可以稍微改一下这个，对吧？
Right.
对。
You can say my fellow co-workers.
你可以说我的同事们。
My fellow citizens.
我的同胞们。
My fellow family members.
我的家人们。
Yes.
是的。
So basically fellow just means like dear.
所以基本上 fellow 就像亲爱的意思。
Yeah.
嗯。
In some way.
在某种程度上。
Well, similar.
嗯，类似。
Similar.
类似。
Yeah.
嗯。
So we looked at some great vocabulary and phrases and now let's talk a little bit about
我们看了一些很棒的词汇和短语，现在我们来谈谈
these American traditions when electing a new president.
这些选举新总统时的美国传统。
Yes.
是的。
Today in the studio we have JP who's joining us.
今天在演播室我们有JP加入我们。
Hi everyone.
大家好。
Hey JP.
嘿，JP。
And he's going to be talking to us about these traditions.
他将和我们聊聊这些传统。
Oh, I am?
哦，是吗？
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
嗯。
What are we going to talk about?
我们要聊什么？
21 gun salute.
21响礼炮。
What's that all about?
那是怎么回事？
The 21 gun salute is the military salute where they say, and now we will have the 21 gun
21响礼炮是一种军事敬礼，他们会说，现在我们将进行21响
salute.
礼炮。
So 21 soldiers with their rifles, they go, and they all shoot them off at the same time.
于是21名士兵带着步枪，他们走过去，同时开枪。
And I don't know why.
我不知道为什么。
I think it's a sign of respect, hey?
我觉得这是一种尊重的表示，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Weird respect though.
不过这种尊重有点奇怪。
Well, I think in Europe they would do a cannon or something.
嗯，我觉得在欧洲他们会用大炮之类的。
Oh, a cannon salute?
哦，鸣炮礼？
No, well, just cannons.
不，就是大炮。
Maybe just one cannon.
可能就一门大炮。
Maybe our European listeners know the answer to this.
也许我们的欧洲听众知道答案。
Maybe.
也许吧。
Okay.
好的。
And what about this song Hail to the Chief?
那这首《向领袖致敬》呢？
Do you know anything about that?
你了解那首歌吗？
I do not know anything about it except that it's a march and I think it's Souza.
除了知道它是一首进行曲，而且我觉得是苏萨写的之外，我什么都不知道。
I think John Philip Souza wrote it.
我觉得是约翰·菲利普·苏萨写的。
And whenever the president walks into a room, they play that song.
每当总统走进房间时，他们就会播放那首歌。
Really?
真的吗？
Yes.
是的。
And I played it once for President Bush, the first one.
我曾经为老布什总统演奏过一次。
I was a drummer.
我以前是个鼓手。
You did?
真的吗？
And my marching band had to play that song for him.
我的军乐队得为他演奏那首歌。
Oh my God, JP, you're like famous.
天哪，JP，你简直像个名人。
Yeah.
是啊。
This was back in like 1986 or something.
那大概是1986年左右的事。
Was that even an election year?
那一年是大选年吗？
88?
88年？
Yeah.
对。
Well, you did play for the president, so you know.
嗯，你毕竟为总统演奏过，所以你知道的。
That's pretty cool.
那挺酷的。
Yeah.
是啊。
So JP, do you have any other sort of traditional things that happen when the president becomes
那么JP，总统就职时还有其他什么传统活动吗？
the president?
成为总统的时候？
Well, I can tell you that Jimmy Carter, you know, when he was elected president, his motorcade
嗯，我可以告诉你，吉米·卡特当选总统时，他的车队
was going down Pennsylvania Avenue and he stopped the car and got out.
正沿着宾夕法尼亚大道行驶，他让车停下并走了出来。
Really?
真的吗？
To do what?
去做什么？
Yeah.
是啊。
To walk.
去散步。
He wanted to walk down Pennsylvania Avenue.
他想沿着宾夕法尼亚大道走。
He wanted to walk down the, you know, down the street.
他想沿着那条，你知道，沿着街道走。
To be with the people?
为了和人民在一起？
Yeah, I think so.
是的，我想是这样。
And I think it made the Secret Service insane.
我觉得这让特勤局抓狂了。
Maybe the car smelled bad or something.
也许车里气味难闻什么的。
Maybe so.
也许吧。
I think that is my memory of it.
我想这就是我的记忆。
I might be confusing with the West Wing, but I'm not sure.
我可能和《白宫风云》搞混了，但我不确定。
Too much TV.
电视看太多了。
Yeah, maybe.
嗯，也许吧。
But when the president walks, it's a big deal.
但总统走路可是件大事。
So JP, do you do anything special for the inauguration ceremony?
那么JP，就职典礼你有什么特别安排吗？
I always take the day off to watch.
我总是请假观看。
You do?
真的吗？
I love watching it.
我喜欢看。
I love, you know, the swearing in ceremony, the ritual of it, the speech.
我喜欢，你知道，宣誓仪式，那种仪式感，还有演讲。
All right, everyone, we're out of time.
好了，各位，我们时间到了。
I hope you enjoyed this political lesson.
希望你们喜欢这堂政治课。
I hope you have a happy inauguration day.
祝你们就职日快乐。
Happy inauguration day, everyone.
大家就职日快乐。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
All right, great.
好了，很好。
We're definitely going to take the day off to watch it with JP.
我们肯定会请假和JP一起看。
And hopefully you guys can too.
希望你们也能。
Well, thanks for listening, everyone.
好了，感谢大家的收听。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
再见。